now this we have seen how the Rob based
processor is supposed to work let's do a
Rob quiz this is actually going to be a
series of quizzes we will have this
state of the processor with these
instructions
note that the add note takes one cycle
multiplication three cycles and divide
takes 10 cycles and the assumptions
about dispatching and execution and so
on are the same as before so basically
if an instruction captures results in
one cycle then it can dispatch in that
cycle and begins executing in the next
cycle or if the instruction is issued in
one cycle and it has operands ready to
go then it can dispatch in that same
cycle so that it begins executing in the
very next cycle but the last cycle of
execution will complete before we
broadcast the results so if an ad begins
executing in some cycle X because it
takes one cycle to do that it's going to
be able to broadcast the result in cycle
X plus one the initial values of the
registers are days the cycle is one
obviously nothing will happen except for
an issuing of an instruction so the
first question for you is we will try to
issue this instruction what is going to
be the content of the rat entry for our
two so put the value here